Rishabh Iyer

rishabh.iyer@berkeley.edu

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a computer systems researcher (broadly construed), and most of my work lies at the intersection of systems, networking, hardware and formal verification. My current research focuses on developing techniques that enable developers to reason precisely about the expected performance of their systems before they are deployed in production. My dissertation work introduced the notion of latency interfaces: simple, succinct programs that summarize a system's latency behaviour just like semantic interfaces such as code documentation and specifications summarize functionality.

EDUCATION

Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne (EPFL)

2017-2023

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Computer Science Thesis: Latency Interfaces for Systems Code

Advisors: Prof. George Candea & Prof. Katerina Argyraki

Indian Institute of Technology Bombay (IITB)

2013-2017

Bachelor of Technology with Honours, Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Performance Modelling and Dynamic Scheduling for Heteregeneous ISA Processors

Advisor: Prof. Virendra Singh

Professional Experience

Postdoctoral Scholar at UC Berkeley

March 2024 - Present

Supervisor: Prof. Sylvia Ratnasamy and Prof. Scott Shenker Working on verifying performance properties of wide-area networks.

Postdoctoral Scholar at EPFL

Sep 2023 - Feb 2024

Supervisor: Prof. George Candea

Worked on a wide range of topics centred around on building systems with predictable performance behavior

Visiting Researcher at UC Berkeley

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

Supervisor: Prof. Sylvia Ratnasamy

Worked on Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators

Summer Intern at EPFL

May - July 2016

Supervisor: Prof. Babak Falsafi

Ported the QFlex Trace Simulator from QEMU 2.3 to QEMU 2.6

Honors & Awards

• eBPF Foundation Research Award

2024

• Eurosys Roger Needham Dissertation Award

2024

• ACM SIGOPS Dennis M. Ritchie Doctoral Dissertation Award

2023

• Thesis nominated by EPFL for ACM Doctoral Dissertation Award

2023

• Best Paper Award

 $VDAT\ 2019$

• EPFL Doctoral Fellowship

2017

Publications

• Fast, Flexible, and Practical Kernel Extensions

Kumar Kartikeya Dwivedi, Rishabh Iyer, Sanidhya Kashyap. Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2024. Acceptance rate: 17.3% Also accepted to the Linux Plumbers Conference (LPC) 2024. eBPF Foundation Research Award 2024.

• Automatically Reasoning About How Systems Code Uses the CPU Cache

Rishabh Iyer, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea.

Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2024. Acceptance rate: 15.6% Also accepted to the Linux Plumbers Conference (LPC) 2024.

• Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators

Jiacheng Ma, Rishabh Iyer, Sahand Kashani, Mahyar Emami, Thomas Bourgeat, George Candea. Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2024. Acceptance rate: 15.6%

• Achieving Microsecond-Scale Tail Latency Efficiently with Approximate Optimal Scheduling Rishabh Iyer, Musa Unal, Marios Kogias, George Candea.

Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2023. Acceptance rate: 18.7%

• The Case for Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators

Rishabh Iyer, Jiacheng Ma, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea, Sylvia Ratnasamy. Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2023. Acceptance rate: 26.4%

• Performance Interfaces for Network Functions

Rishabh Iyer, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea.

Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2022. Acceptance rate: 19.7%

• Bypassing the Load Balancer Without Regrets.

Marios Kogias, Rishabh Iyer, Edouard Bugnion.

Symposium on Cloud Computing (SoCC), 2020. Acceptance rate: 24.4%

• Classification-Based Scheduling in Heterogeneous-ISA Architectures

Nirmal Boran, Dinesh Yadav, Rishabh Iver.

Symposium on VLSI Design and Test (VDAT), 2020. Acceptance rate: 28.7%

• Verifying Software Network Functions with No Verification Expertise

Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Solal Pirelli, <u>Rishabh Iyer</u>, Luis Pedrosa, Matteo Rizzo, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea.

Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2019. Acceptance rate: 13.7%

• Performance Modelling and Dynamic Scheduling on Heterogeneous-ISA Architectures

Nirmal Boran, Dinesh Yadav, Rishabh Iyer

Symposium on VLSI Design and Test (VDAT), 2019. Acceptance rate: 27.3%

Awarded Best Paper

• Performance Contracts for Software Network Functions

Rishabh Iyer, Luis Pedrosa, Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Solal Pirelli, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea. Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019. Acceptance rate: 14.7%

• Automated Synthesis of Adversarial Workloads for Network Functions

Luis Pedrosa, Rishabh Iyer, Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Jonas Fietz, Katerina Argyraki. *ACM SIGCOMM Conference (SIGCOMM)*, 2018. Acceptance rate: 18%

TEACHING

CS 522: Principles of Computer Systems (EPFL)

Assistantships CS 305: Software Engineering (EPFL)

MA 207: Analysis 4 - Vector Calculus (EPFL)

PH 107: Quantum Physics (IITB)

Fall 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022

Fall 2018

Spring 2018, 2019

Fall 2022 - Present

Fall 2014

RESEARCH MENTORSHIP

• Jiacheng Ma (PhD student at EPFL)

Performance interfaces for hardware accelerators

Second author on publication at HotOS'23, lead author on publication at OSDI'24.

• Musa Unal (PhD student at EPFL)

Summer 2022 - Fall 2023

Cooperative scheduling for microsecond-scale datacenter applications

Second author on publication at SOSP'23.

Summer 2023 - Present

• Kumar Kartikeya Dwivedi (PhD student at EPFL) Fast, flexible, and practical kernel extensions

Lead author on publication at SOSP'24

• Ayoub Chouak (summer intern at EPFL)

Summer 2021

Leveraging performance interfaces to identify constant-time violations in cryptographic code Significant contributor to publication at NSDI'22.

• Yugesh Kothari (PhD student at EPFL)
Performance interfaces for eBPF offloads in the Linux kernel
Significant contributor to the PIX open source tool.

Spring 2024 - Present

Fall 2022

• Alexander Krenstsel (PhD student at UC Berkeley) Input Validation for Software-Defined Wide Area Networks Lead author on submission to HotNets 2024.

Spring 2024 - Present

• Ziming Mao (PhD student at UC Berkeley) Revisiting cache freshness for emerging real-time applications Lead author on submission to HotNets 2024.

Fall 2022 - Present

Rathin Singla (PhD student at UCLA)
 A verified, extensible transport stack
 Lead author on submission to HotNets 2024.

Fall 2022 - Spring 2023

• Narek Galstyan (PhD student at UC Berkeley) Application-integrated record and replay for distributed systems